The Princess Sapphire
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Princess Knight,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Thirty-First Episode
The Kingdom of the Seas
I like the sea,
because it is big!
There is the little turtle
on the turtle's back!
There is the turtle
on the big turtle's back!
If Grandpa falls, they all fall!
Whoops!
How cruel they are!
Halt! Wait!
Why are you mistreating the turtles?
What did they do wrong to you?
Leave them alone!
What do you want, kid? Go away,
otherwise we'll mistreat you too!
All right!
This is the money earned
by guarding the sheep!
I'm giving it to you,
but leave the turtles alone!
It's only 10 Yen!
Don't make fun of us!
Take that!
Bad boys, you shouldn't
mistreat a child.
The turtle spoke!
You shouldn't fight.
Help! Let's run away!
Thanks for the help.
You don't have to thank me.
I tried to help you, it's true,
but you gave me
a much greater help.
We were looking for exactly
a kind person like you.
- Do you want to help us?
- Help you?!
Yes! Come with us, let's
go to the dragon's palace.
To the dragon's palace?!
No! I don't want to come!
What are you doing? I don't
know how to swim! Sapphire!
Tink!
Tink! Tink!
- Can I go with you?
- I'm looking for Tink...
...and I have no need
of you, Nylon!
But I want to help you anyway!
Two people can search better, right?
- Tink! Tink!
- Hey! Wait, please!
I'm telling you again that
I don't know how to swim!
If we go to the dragon's
palace, I'll drown!
Please,
stay with us to help us!
But the dragon's palace
is at the bottom of the sea!
And I am afraid
of the depths of the sea!
Ah, you're here, Tink! Get up!
Get up, please! We've arrived!
Where am I?
You're at the bottom of the sea!
At the bottom of the sea?!
But how come I haven't drowned?
Now let's go
to the dragon's palace.
My mother and my grandfather
are waiting for us.
And Princess Neptune is there too
Who is Princess Neptune?
She's our Princess
There are sharks! Let's run away!
Wait a moment!
I think I hear..
Yes, there's a ship
passing above us.
Pull it down, so I can
eat some pastries!
I'm fed up with the food
at the dragon's palace.
It's bad and too wet!
Hey, you, little turtle!
- What is it?
- Who is that funny little boy..
...who is with you?
- He's a guest of mine.
A guest? Give him to me!
- No, I won't give it to you!
- Shut up!
It's really very funny...
I'll put it
in my little private zoo!
- Give it to me!
- No!
Wait!
Let's duck in here!
What a racket!
One can't get any sleep!
Hey, you, big head! Have you hidden
someone in that big mouth of yours?
Let me see!
Open this sort of trapdoor!
My henchmen managed
to pull down the ship.
Good job! Quite a nice haul!
Tasty pastries...! Hey,
where are you going?
To look for a quieter
little spot!
I really want to see
if I can manage to take a nap.
- Let us out! Let us out!
- Dammit!
- Can I just know what...?!
- Let us out! Let us out!
You're giving me
a stomachache!
Thank you! You saved our lives!
But who are those two?
Now we are going
to the Dragon Palace.
The Dragon Palace is cursed.
Right?
In the past it was very beautiful,
then the sharks destroyed it
almost completely.
King Neptune, I've brought a guest!
King Neptune!
Hey, you, don't shout!
Or the palace will collapse!
You've arrived, finally.
Yes, I'm here! And now you'll tell me
what I have to do to help you.
We brought you here
to help Princess Neptune.
The Princess?!
She's King Neptune's daughter, right?
Where is she? I want to see her!
Princess Neptune
is no longer here.
- Is she dead?
- No, she's not dead
- But...
- "But", what?
I am King Neptune.
Welcome to the dragon palace.
You are a child
with a kind heart, right?
My name is Tink.
Tink? What a strange name!
You seem different
from ordinary people.
You see,
I am not a human being.
I am an angel!
Do you know of angels?
An angel?! Oh, heavens!
Please, Mr. Angel Tink,
help my daughter,
Princess Neptune! Please!
What happened
to Princess Neptune?
Come with me,
Mr. Angel Tink.
Come, let's go forward
Princess Neptune
is in here.
Where? I don't see anything.
Now I'll get you some light.
Lantern-fish!
Here I am, I'm here!
Light the lantern, please.
How big this shell is!
Princess Neptune shut herself
in there four years ago...
...and hasn't wanted to come out since.
- Four years?!
And why did she lock herself away?
Oh, a bad thing happened
four years ago.
Since then, no one has
managed to get her to come out.
Mr. Angel Tink, please,
you make her come out!
Shell! Shell, please,
open up! Please, shell!
It's opening!
Please, open up, shell!
Let the Princess out!
It's closing again! Princess
Neptune, don't close!
Shell! Shell! please, open up!
King Neptune wants so
much to see Princess Neptune!
He feels so lonely without
her! Please, open up!
Princess, come out!
She's coming out! We've waited
for you so long, Princess Neptune!
No! Princess Neptune,
why won't you come out?
- Why did you come?
- Why are you meddling?
Go away!
Shut up!
But where did he go?
We need Sapphire! Without
her, I can't do anything!
Tink! Tink!
Him again!
Do you really not want me to
help you find your little friend?
I'm very skilled at
finding things, you know?
I don't need you!
And stop following me!
While I am following you,
it will certainly happen...
...the opportunity to kill
you! I am very stubborn!
I will find a way to cut off
that beautiful little head!
What?! Tink was
kidnapped by the turtles?
Yes! He went out to
sea together with them.
Oh, Tink..!
Princess Sapphire, where are you
going with such a fragile little boat?
- I'm going to look for Tink!
- What?!
Tink! Tink!
It's a gift from heaven!
With that wretched boat...
...she will drown before she
manages to reach the open sea!
Now Sapphire will
die! How happy I am!
Tink!
Let me go! Let me go!
King Shark, you promised
me not to use violence!
Ah, but you haven't
kept your promise either!
I will keep it! This
time I will keep it!
Really? Then you will give
me your daughter as a wife...
..as you promised
four years ago?
As a wife?!
Well, yes, I...
I love Princess Neptune!
But when will she come out?
- Today.
- I can no longer trust you.
You know, I've waited for her
for four very long years!
And... I can't wait any longer!
Wait, please! I will manage
to get her to come out, so wait!
Alright, I will wait for a
little longer, but hurry up!
Understood?!
Mr. Angel Tink, please,
make the Princess come out!
No! I will never allow
him to marry her! Never!
Mr. Tink, please!
Princess Neptune!
Did you hide there because you
didn't want to marry King Shark?
- Yes! But who are you?
- I am Tink, Princess!
Don't worry,
I will try to protect you!
Mr. Tink,
I must keep the promise,
even if it's an old promise.
Why did you make
such a promise?
To put an end to the violence
of King Shark.
He told me that if I gave
him my daughter in marriage,
he would stop tyrannizing
the weaker fish.
I will not allow the shell
to open!
Mr. Tink, it was
to protect the weak fish.
Please, try to understand!
Turtles,
let's all protect the Princess!
If we unite,
we won't be eaten by the sharks!
It's true! It's true! Let's unite!
You don't know the cruelty
of King Shark.
A ship is passing, I can feel it
Pull down that ship
and bring me whoever is on board!
Tink! Tink!
Let's hope he hasn't drowned
and that he is still alive!
My God!
Well done! You've done
a really good job!
This is the pill of oblivion. You
will take it, so you will forget everything
.and you will do what I tell you!
That's fine.
Let's go, now.
Now bring me some clothes
Go and put on one
of these dresses! Quickly!
Sapphire?!
I want to show it
to Princess Neptune.
After four years,
she must be dressed out of fashion!
Now spread all the clothes
on the stage!
Open that shell!
Up! Lift it!
Sapphire, I'm happy to see you!
Listen...
Listen, Sapphire..
. Who are you? What do you
want from me? I don't know you!
What?!
Sapphire! Sapphire, let me out!
It's Tink! Sapphire! Sapphire!
Mr. Tink!
King Neptune, let's fight
against the Shark King...
...together with the other fish!
We can't fight against
him! He's too strong!
He's a bully! He'll kill us all!
Oh, Tink!
- Princess Neptune!
- Let's celebrate the wedding right away!
If you marry her, will
you stop being so violent?
I really don't know!
- My father!
- My daughter!
Do you want to tell me what
happened to you, Sapphire?
I don't know, I don't remember anything!
But what are you saying? Is it
possible you don't remember me?
I am Tink! Turn
around! And look at me!
And what is this?
Tink, why are we in
this place? Tell me, why?
There, it's open!
Now let's hurry!
She's here! She's crying!
Be quiet!
Look, the bride is coming!
Now let's begin!
King Shark, do you swear that you
will make Princess Neptune your wife...
..and abolish forever violence?
Well, yes, I swear it!
And you, Princess Neptune,
even if you wouldn't want to...
...be the bride of King
Shark, do you swear anyway...
...to put up with him and to
live together with him peacefully?
Well, what's gotten into you now?!
Do you want to swear it or not?
Answer now, otherwise I'll
get angry right away, you know?
Please, swear it! Please!
Swear, or else...
And who are you?!
Go, Sapphire! Defeat them!
Before we were weak, but now
that we are united, we are strong!
Come on, get them!
Well done! Well done!
Shell, please, open up!
We won! We won!
- Mr. Tink!
- We won!
Hurray! We won! Hurray!
Thank you, Sapphire! And
thank you too, Tink!
What a pity I couldn't fight too!
- What’s happening, Sapphire?
- Damn it!
I just remembered now that
one day in the dragon's palace...
...corresponds to 50 years
in the human world! Right?
My God, then we must
go back as soon as possible!
Please, wait, Sapphire.
They say that this box...
...grants wishes. Open it
when you are in trouble.
Goodbye! Goodbye!
- Goodbye!
I can't wait to get there.
I wonder if our friends have
already become old people...
It's Nylon! What happened to him?
He seems to have turned to stone!
I'm scared! I wonder what
happened...! Let's try to open the box!
What will happen when we open it?
We could become an old
man and an old woman.
I don't want to become an old man!
We haven't changed! Thank goodness!
It's a gift from heaven!
Sapphire must have drowned!
I'm so happy!
Hey! I thought you were both dead!
What happened instead?
Nothing strange happened.
I had asked the Gods of heaven to stop time in the world,
while you were helping me.
Now that the box is open,
time has started to pass again.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP